Guide to the Stanford University, Program on Urban Studies, Honors Theses
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Program on Urban Studies, honors theses
1987-2013
SC4-6532
Stanford University. Program on Urban Studies.
3 Linear feet (54 volumes in 8 boxes)
Honors theses written by undergraduate students in the Stanford University Program on Urban Studies.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Materials were transferred to the Stanford University Archives by the Program on Urban Studies in several accessions from 2006-2012. Additional theses were transferred from the Hume Writing Center in 2011.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use. No photocopies may be made.
Scope and Contents note
The collection consists of honors theses written by undergraduate students in the Stanford University Program on Urban Studies.
Arrangement note
Materials are arranged alphabetically by author's last name within each accession.
Access Terms
Stanford University. Program on Urban Studies.; Cities and towns; Student papers.
Collection Contents
- Honors Theses, 2006; Accession ARCH-2006-181
  - Adachi, Maiko Emi, Gentrification and Neighborhood Life in Chicago., May 2006 (Box 1)
  - Cordova, Rashel, The promise of prefab: the challenges and advantages of integrating prefabrication into the multi-famity housing industry., 2006 (Box 1)
  - Surm, Laura Lyndsey, The show must go on: relighting the marquee at Palo Alto's Varsity Theatre., May 2006 (Box 1)
- Honors Theses, 2007; Accession ARCH-2007-153
  - Chan, Deland, How Migrant Workers Find Housing in Beijing: The role of individual agency in differential housing access and outcomes., 2007 (Box 1)
  - Feiger, Lola, Memorialization of Urban Concentration Camps: Reading the Scale and Infrastructural Complexity of Sachsenhausen for an Understanding of the Holocaust., May 2007 (Box 1)
  - Goldman, Alexandra, Beyond Maquinas de Dinero: A Case Study of a Low-Income Worker Cooperative., May 2007 (Box 1)
  - Miller, Colin, Instruments of Peace: Music, Community Development, and Environmental Justice in a Brazilian Neighborhood., May 2007 (Box 1)
- Honors Theses, 2008; Accession ARCH-2008-296
  - Fagliano, Stephanie, How victim-offender mediation impacts juvenile offenders; what it offers and who it benefits., May 2008 (Box 1)
  - Finch, Kelsey, Trouble in paradise: postwar history of San Francisco's Hunters Point neighborhood., May 2008 (Box 1)
  - Reovan, Andrew, Theme park in the city: Disneyland and the aesthetic of the "Anaheim Resort"., May 2008 (Box 1)
  - Sands, Ted, Demystifying Silicon Valley's urban legend; an econometric analysis of land prices and zoning in Milpitas, California., 2008 (Box 1)
  - Thielke, Claire Cormier, Shabby chic; colleges, refurbished structures, and urban revitalization: a case study of Houston Community College central campus., 2008 (Box 1)
  - Warshawsky, Debbie, This is My Ghetto: exploring agency and efficacy among public housing residents in East Harlem., 2008 (Box 1)
- Honors Theses, 2009; Accession ARCH-2009-203
  - Demong, Stefanie, "I'm a better human being"; exploring family adjustment to autism., 2009 (Box 1)
  - Leblanc, Stany, Partnership for success: the effects of parents and parental initiative programs on student educational aspirations and achievement., 2009 (Box 1)
- Honors Theses, 2010; Accession ARCH-2010-086
  - de la Torre, Justin Dane, Yes we can: same-sex marriage, legitimacy, and agency., 2010 (Box 1)
  - Jones, Melissa Ann, The power of memory: urban transformation and historical representation on the San Francisco waterfront., 2010 (Box 1)
  - Martinez, Katie, Participation, politics and planning: the impact of citizen participation in Palo Alto, California., 2010 (Box 1)
- Honors Theses, 2011; Accession ARCH-2011-150
  - Bassett, Angela, From Local Intervention to Global Solution: Culture in Mental Health and Sangath., 2011
  - Carollo, George, Working Towards Sustainable Commutes: An Analysis of Cyclists on Caltrain and BART., 2011 (Box 1)
  - Chan, Gary, Re-Constructing Hayes Valley: Place Branding and Community in a Revitalizing Neighborhood., 2011 (Box 1)
  - Jones, Emily, "As Good as It Gets": Life in San Francisco's SRO Hotels., 2011 (Box 1)
  - Kwan, Helen, Saddling Up for the World Equestrian Games: Lexington, KY's Preparation for and Response to a Mega-event., 2011 (Box 1)
  - Martinez-Tavera, Karla, Population Aging: An Integrated Approach: The Example of Fortaleza, Brazil., 2011 (Box 1)
  - Moskitis, Shannon, "It's a Catch 22": The Intersection of Homelessness, Domestic Violence, and the Shelter System's Response., 2011 (Box 1)
  - Orbuch, Eva, Towards an Integrated Approach to Microfinance: A Case for the Integration of Financial and Non-Financial Services in Microfinance Institutions., 2011 (Box 1)
  - Read, Annie, Getting Involved: How Summer Enrichment Programs Improve Social Development and Behavior., 2011 (Box 1)
- Honors Theses, Accession ARCH-2011-152
  - Kyle, Selena, There goes the neighborhood: the failure and promise of second units as a housing source for the Midpeninsula., 2000 (Box 1)
  - Lange, Mindy, A small town sprawls: a closer look at development issues in Muscatine, Iowa., 1998 (Box 1)
  - Margolin, Dale, Does teen court work? A case study of Santa Cruz Teen Court., 1999 (Box 1)
  - Mathewson, Colin, Students today, leaders tomorrow: limiting community expectations of youth and the future of civic engagement., 2002 (Box 1)
  - Tinto, Eda Katharine, Integrating race and family: a reconsideration of transracial adoption., 1996 (Box 1)
  - Jacobson, Brad, Strategic defense initiatives: public space in the fear-full American city., 1995 (Box 1)
  - Johnson, Emily S., The challenges of collaborative planning: an examination of major issues in five community park projects in Seattle WA., 1999 (Box 1)
  - Arroyo, Kathleen Mary, The Northern Ireland Agreement and its affects on the architecture and city planning of Belfast., 2000 (Box 1)
  - Sun, Stephanie, Learning from Hong Kong: journey, object, fact, and fiction in a city of spectacle., 2002 (Box 1)
  - Sakamoto, Naomi Noelani Kam Yuk, Airspace., 2003 (Box 1)
  - Oscherwitz, William S., New towns: a step toward Utopia., 1987 (Box 1)
  - Brawner, Christie, ¡A la minga! Andean reciprocity and strategies for social service delivery., 2003 (Box 1)
- Honors Theses, 2012; Accession ARCH-2012-050
  - Jacobson, Daniel, Silicon Valley Infill Development Analysis., 2012 (Box 1)
  - Knox, Tamara, The Impact of Rail on Economic Growth: A Case Study of the Los Angeles Red Line., 2012 (Box 1)
  - Fernandez, Erica, Effects of Land Use Change and Urban Development on Biodiversity and Traditional Ecological Knowledge in a Maya Community in Yucatan., 2012 (Box 1)
  - Miller, Matthew J., From Dust to Dust: Mapping Race and Risk to PCB Explosure in West Oakland's Soil, Food, and Water from 1940-2000., 2012 (Box 1)
  - Chan, Stephanie K., The Waizhou Special: Exploring the Effects of Immigrant Diffusion on Chinese Restaurant Workers in McMinnville, Tennessee., 2012 (Box 1)
  - Hanono, Gerald Benjamin, California Dreamin': Examining the Legacy of the Great Tax Revolt in Chula Vista, California., 2012 (Box 1)
- Honors Theses, 2013; Accession ARCH-2013-055
  - Bulkeley-Krane, Dylan The Importance of Being Urban: The Role of Cities in the 2012 Presidential Election, 2013 May (Box 1)
  - Dillon, Natalie Exploring the Broken Windows Theory: A Spatial Analysis of Graffiti and Crime in San Francisco, 2013 May (Box 1)
  - Gibson, Kimberly Arrival of the City: The Impacts of Urban Expansion on Periurban Agricultural Communities of Sangareddy, India, 2013 May (Box 1)
  - Heredia, Rachel Grantmaking Foundations' Use of Social Media: A Comparison Across Location, Age, and Donation Structure, 2013 May (Box 1)
  - Jor, Irene Strategic Engagement: A Case Study on Building Coalition with Disabled Employers for the California Domestic Workers Bill of Rights (AB 889), 2013 May (Box 1)
  - Ponting, Anna High Tech Urbanism: The Political and Econmic Implications of the Smart City, 2013 May (Box 1)
  - Princen, Paul Place-Based Corporate Social Entrepreneurship: A Case Study of Whole Foods, 2013 May (Box 1)
  - Stevens McAdam, Taylor Global Trends and Local Choices: A Comparison of Young Italian and American Food Practices, 2013 May (Box 1)
  - Yuen-Shore, Jamie Exploring Perceptions of Asian Identity: Through Conversations with Asian American Mothers and their Mixed-Asian White Daughters, 2013 May (Box 1)